This is something we shall be really familiar with,
but when it comes to growing as a view developer,
a lot of times, most of us are not so lucky
as to inherit a brand new code base, right?
We usually have things that we're working with,
that are brand new or more importantly,
you know, managers want us to ship quickly,
so we bring in third party libraries and we wrap stuff up.
But there is a question of how we properly manage those dependencies,
because any of us who've done this long enough knows
that redesigns often happen,
and so having to rip out internals and refactor things
is something that's common.
And so what are some techniques we can do
to kind of manage this particular problem?
All right, so let's go ahead and take a look at the code that we have.
So inside of our app, again, this is our standard view
three app we're using view three router here.
You'll notice here that we have a lot going on,
basically we're using Daisy UI from a tailwind perspective,
so like that's like the UI library being used.
And one of the things that's being used a lot,
and one that I think we can all share as a common pain point,
is this icon component.
And so this is from Daisy View, Daisy UI,
in fact, this is from Iconify.
And so we look at the number of instances of icon.
You can see that it's actually used,
as well, it's used quite a lot.
And so this might not seem like a big deal at first,
but as we know, design requirements do change,
and oftentimes they'll come in and they'll want a random one off,
or they'll want something changed about it.
And so the question boils around,
like how do we actually manage those changes and requests?
And so let's say for instance,
that a designer has discovered this amazing resource,
which if you are not aware of, you should also be aware of,
and it's called icons.js.org.
And it's basically this collection of free icons across a lot of different ones.
And so for example, if I want to look up like mountain icon,
they'll give me a bunch from the different libraries.
And what's cool about this is that I can pick anyone of these,
let's choose this one, for example.
And then it'll tell me where it came from,
but then you can also let you generate basically like the SVG,
or in this case, we can actually just click and copy the view component,
you know, just populate that for you.
And so let's say the designer wants this because what they want to do
is they want to replace this icon that we have in the upper left.
They want to replace it with a mountain instead.
And so we know for a fact that this icon does not exist inside the icon,
if I view.
And so what you might be originally tempted to do is probably just either
dropping the SVG or a custom component just in that one point.
But as we know with Enterprise Act, things blow really quickly,
things get reused.
And so what we want to do is try to, as much as possible,
maintain a single source of truth,
that way we can centralize everything.
And more importantly, when changes are being made or being swapped out,
it's a lot easier to refactor and more importantly, easier to maintain.
So how might we do this?
So first thing first, I'll go ahead and create a component here,
inside the component folder.
I usually like to create a dedicated icons folder.
So I'll call this icon mountain view.
And then I'll just paste basically the template that they generate for us earlier.
And so you see here, we just have a simple SVG.
It has some widths defined as well as a view box.
And so overall looks fairly straightforward.
So I'm just going to go ahead and actually switch the name here,
just icon mountain to simplify it.
And so, as I mentioned before, one of these we want to do is centralize the work that we're doing,
because as we saw when we looked at the icons, there are just so many different variations here.
There's a lot of different widths going on as well as trying to figure out,
okay, what exactly are we standardizing on?
Especially if you want to start with like,
all icons just start with 20 by 20 size, for example.
That would be pretty tricky to do, especially if you're just doing a search end replace.
And so the pattern that I generally recommend when it comes to this,
is known as a vendor wrapper component.
And so what that essentially does is it allows us to basically create a wrapper around the UI library
components that we're using as a way to basically provide this single source to truth.
And so the way that we look is that we would go ahead and create a base icon component.
And so I'm going to use a little snippet here that I have basically this is a VS code snippet,
and so just in case anyone is not sure what this is.
And it basically allows me to scaffold a single file component
uh, basically instantly, like that.
How do you do that SFC shortcut?
The which one?
SFC.
Oh yes, oh cool, I'm glad you asked about this.
So when you're in VS code, if you go to your extension,
so I'll do the command prompt way so command shift P,
and then we'll go to our extensions.
Can I just see my extensions?
All right, the way I do it is command K E, but it aren't X, but anyways, it's right here.
So Sarah Drasner, who used to be on the view core team and now is at Google,
she created this thing called View VS Code snippets.
And so highly recommended as an extension, and so I actually am one of the maintainers.
So it has a bunch of different basically snippets for like things that you like to use.
So whether, so you can see here that like if you do like, uh, so okay, let's see V base SS, right?
So if I come inside here, and I'm inside of my view, V base.
So you see here, there's like a bunch of different ones you can choose from,
and then it'll just kind of, you can basically customize it.
So the thing though is that you can install it, definitely play around with it,
but what's, what I really love about the repo is that once you look at it,
and you find one that you're like, I like that one, I just want to tweak it a little bit.
VS Code snippets are actually fairly easy to create on your own, so then you're basically
you're just copy it, be like, oh, I don't use SAS, I use less or post CSS, I just use hell in whatever,
then you don't have to deal with like the, the boilerplate that comes with it.
Okay, so we know a couple of things. We know one, we want to make sure we migrate all of the icons
over, I can't apply, and so let's go ahead and do that first. So, look, search.
So we have this import that we're going to grab here, and then we know as well that this is the general
structure that we see at least for the iconify one. And so what's interesting though is that you'll
see here that in the iconify icon, they use icon in order as like the prop to designate what the name is.
But if you use other icon libraries as well, you'll notice that the API for it is different as
well. So that's one of the reasons the vendor wrapper icon can be very advantageous, because for our
example with the mountain icon, right? So I inch toward the icon mountain, for example, what we probably
want to do then is we need to do two things. One, we need to set what our default is, and then basically
what our override is going to be. So the default is, at this point, going to be iconify view,
because this is obviously where a bulk of our icons are living. So what I like to do generally
in this situation is we define a prop here, where we basically have the source be type of string,
and then I default it to the main library that we're actually using. And so in this regard,
so here we can say vif to do do do do, right? Source is equal to iconify.
And then we go ahead and then designate the rest of it so we can say, okay, how do we want this API
to look? Do we want to just call it icon? Or in this case, I do think what I've seen more normally,
especially when it comes to icon naming is just the name itself. So then we can have a name string here
and we'll go ahead and require it. And then we can bind this directly to name as well.
And then we can go ahead and then with and height are also very common as well. So we'll go ahead
and also just go ahead and designate those as well. So then default 20 and then we'll just copy this
and make that height. And here we have the beginnings of our wrapper icon.
Okay, so of course the question is now we need to deal with this icon mountain. How do we deal with this?
Now if we think about this from another perspective, while it's easy to say, all right,
what we're going to do is we're going to bring icon mountain here down here and we're just going to
basically like veals. You could do something as simple as that if you really want to. However, obviously
when it comes to scale, it's not going to work as well as you think. So what we ultimately want to do
is provide the user the ability to basically define their name and then we're going to dynamically
import that as it goes. So the way you do that is there is a helper function in view called
define a sync component. And so what that's going to like do is basically define a path that
can be brought in, basically based on how it's defined. So what I'm going to do here is then also
I'm going to bring in computer as well because we're going to go ahead and make first we need to
refer to our props. So I'm going to find it to a variable. And so then we're going to say,
so our custom icons is going to be a computer value where basically if props.source is equal to
or basically in this case we can say not equal to iconify. We can even go that far to say that at this point.
Then we could say basically return define a sync component and then that takes a function that
returns basically an import statement of the path. So in this case it'll be components. I believe
I put it in icons. Yep. And then slash and then I can go ahead and just do the props.name.view.
And then otherwise we'll just return no. Okay. Let's see. So let's see. It's
can not find corresponding type declarations that is fine for now because this is a dynamically
being brought in. Oh, I see what it is. Hang on. There you go. Yay for syntax highlighting.
Okay. So now that you have this, what you can do is view has the built in dynamic component. So now we can say
basically say for the component dynamic component we're going to make that equivalent to using the
is parameter is prop to say custom icon. And so we're going to do now then is going to go ahead and
find that header that we had. So app.view header here. So we have this icon here right with the target.
We no longer want that. What we're going to do instead is we're just going to import our base icon
and so this will go ahead and drag import that directly right here. Although sometimes it does
it incorrectly and as a type. So that's actually a little bit frustrating sometimes. And then I'll say
source. I have to say custom and then the name is going to be icon mountain. And now that we save,
you can see voila. We have our base icon. And so this pattern is incredibly effective for
essentially helping you centralize these things. And so I won't go through the process right now
of like doing all the replace of the base icon. I'll do that later when we're doing exercises.
But so this is the concept of the vendor wrapper. Now the other technique that I do want to
mention here with the base icon is let me queue the slide here. It's known as the v-bind v on syntax.
So here typically you would have like again let's say we wanted to customize the width to like 30
and then the height also to 30. You know what's here one it's broken because partly because
on the base icon I did not define the various props on here directly. So I'll go ahead and just
copy this over real quick just so we can get rid of that error. A string is not assignable to number.
All right we'll deal with that later. So what you can do actually is that in the event that you
want to make this dynamic right so let's go ahead and say for example that we have custom source
and it would just make this a ref real quick just to demonstrate this. And then we'll call this
font awesome. And then we had a constant name equals ref and we'll call this upside down mountain
and then we had constant width which is a ref of let's say 40 then we have our custom height.
So one way you could define this is you could go ahead and come in and then v-bind each one of these
individually. So this should look familiar to most people.
You could do it like this. However, a lot of times when we're working with dynamic components you
can't always control what attributes are being, it's really worth swapping out components.
You're going to be swapping out different properties, different events. And so if you're hard
coding them like this you're going to have basically extra code being passed to your components
that don't need to be. And so what you can do instead is this can all actually be shortcut it to
this v-bind syntax where you basically have an object and this is where the thing that we see here
would be equivalent to this. And then what's nice about this is you can take this one step further
in that if we just assume again let's say props object.
And then you just basically did the source, the name and then the width and the height here
is going to be going to assume this with height.
This whole thing can be swapped down into just props object.
And this is the reason I wanted to go over this is because this is going to be very common
as we go through the rest of the patterns where we're going to be basically doing v-bind on
dynamic attributes where we don't know what's being passed and so we basically need to just
spread it out on the component and we kind of decide what's going on. And so this also, I won't
demonstrate this explicitly, but in the event you have multiple events as well like
mouse down, key up what not there's an equivalent for call it the events object, right?
We can just write an object that pairs your events to whatever you want to function to want to
sign them to. So both these are basically what they call the v-bind v-on objects in text.